inc42.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Inc42 Media

As used in this Privacy Policy, “Inc42” refers to all websites (including Inc42.com)

By visiting Inc42, and accepting our privacy policy, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Last Updated On 23rd  May, 2018

 **What Types of User Information Does Inc42 Obtain?**

You have choices about the data we collect. When you are asked to provide personal data, you may decline. But if you choose not to provide data that is necessary to enable us to provide the Services, you may not be able to use all or part of those Services.

The data we collect depends on the context of your interactions with Inc42, the choices you make (including your privacy settings), and the Services you use. 

Inc42 may obtain the following types of information from you or concerning your computer or device (“Information”), which may include information that can be used to identify you as specified below (“Personally Identifiable Information”):

  * Name
  * Email Address
  * Mailing Address
  * Telephone Number(s)
  * Blog or Website URL
  * Photo
  * Demographic Information (e.g., age, gender, interests, and preferences)
  * Professional Title
  * Company
  * Industry
  * Activities or Content Viewed on Inc42

In certain cases, we may request that you provide some of the Information identified above in order to obtain specific products or services (such as registering for an Inc42 event or logging in to download a research report from Inc42). You may choose not to provide the Information we request. However, if you chose not to share the informations, you may still use Inc42, but you may be unable to access certain features or services.

When you register to receive any products or services from Inc42 or provide information to Inc42 in any other manner, you agree to provide only true, accurate, current and complete information.

 **Information Collected Automatically**

Inc42 may automatically receive and log certain types of information when you visit or interact with our websites, services, mobile applications or other products, including:

  * Browser Information
  * Operating System Information
  * Mobile Device Information (e.g., device identifier, mobile operating system, etc.)
  * IP Address
  * Internet Service Provider
  * Content Viewed
  * Geographic Location
  * Connection Speed
  * Time of Visit
  * Referring Site, Application, or Service
  * Registration Time

You may choose to view or delete your information collected automatically by inc42 by raising a request through [https://inc42.com/contact/](https://inc42.com/contact/)

 **How Do We Use This Information?**

We use the Information we obtain from or concerning you or your computer or device to provide Inc42 products and services, fulfill your requests, improve our products and services, personalize and tailor your experience on Inc42, operate our business, and understand how users are engaging with Inc42.

We use the data to provide and improve the Services we offer, and to perform essential business operations. This includes operating the Services, maintaining and improving the performance of the Services, developing new features, conducting research, and periodically provide promotional materials or notifications related to our products and services to the email address associated with your account. Examples of such uses include the following:

 **Providing the Services** : We use data to carry out your transactions with us and to provide the Services to you. In certain cases, the Services include personalized features and recommendations that enhance your productivity and enjoyment, and automatically tailor your experience based on the data we have about you.

 **Technical support:** We use data to diagnose product problems, and to provide other customer support and services.

 **Improving the Services:** We use data to continually improve our website and our Services, including system administration, system security, and adding new features or capabilities.

 **Business Operations:** We use data to develop aggregate analyses and business intelligence that enable us to operate, protect, make informed decisions, and report on the performance of our business.

 **Promotions:** We may use your data to administer contests, promotions, surveys, or other site features.

 **Improving Advertising Campaigns:** We may use your data to improve our advertising campaigns, primarily in an effort to prevent targeting of impressions via third-party channels when they are not relevant to you.

 **Sending Emails and Newsletters:** We may use your data to send you periodic emails and newsletters. Depending on the marketing preferences you select while subscribing for our emails, we may send you occasional marketing emails and newsletters about our products and services, which you can unsubscribe from at any time using the link provided in the message.

 **In General:** We use data to respond to your inquiries and requests relating to our Services, to create and administer your accounts, and to provide us with information and access to resources that you have requested from us. We also use data for general business purposes, including, among other things, to improve customer service, to help us improve the content and functionality of our Services, to better understand our users, to protect against wrongdoing or plagiarism. 

**Inc42’s Use of Cookies**

Inc42 may place “cookies” on your computer or device that may contain anonymous Information that is associated with you. Cookies are small text files a website uses to recognize users, and are typically placed on your hard disk by a web server. Cookies contain information that can later be read by a web server in the domain (here, Inc42) that issued the cookie to you or that, in some cases, can be read by a third party domain.

Our cookies may record Information about your use of Inc42 so that we can provide a continuous and more personalized experience for you, including for one or more of the following purposes: to help identify visitors; assess usage patterns; identify preferences; control the display of ads; diagnose problems with our servers; gather demographic information; analyze trends and usage patterns; conduct research; deliver editorial content; record registration and personalized information; and otherwise administer Inc42 products and services.

If you do not wish to have Inc42 place and use cookies on your computer, you should set your browser preferences to refuse cookies before accessing Inc42. Inc42 is not responsible for any failure by you or your browser to accurately implement or communicate your browser preferences or settings. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of Inc42 that depend on cookies.

 **Inc42 does not control and is not responsible for the use of cookies by its third party partners or advertisers**.

 **Keeping Your Data Confidential, & Resilient**

We implement a variety of measures to ensure that our processing systems remain confidential, resilient, and available. Specifically, we have implemented processes to help ensure high availability, business continuity, and prompt disaster recovery. We commit to maintaining strong physical and logical access controls.

Every part of the Services utilize properly-provisioned, redundant servers (e.g., multiple load balancers, web servers, replica databases) in case of failure. We take servers out of operation as part of regular maintenance, without impacting availability.

We keep encrypted backups of data every hour in multiple regions. While never expected, in the case of production data loss (i.e., primary data stores loss), we will restore organizational data from these backups.

 **Recovery** : In the event of a region-wide outage, we will bring up a duplicate environment in a different region. Our operations team has extensive experience performing full region migrations.

 **Access Controls** : inc42 is hosted on AWS. Amazon has many years of experience in designing, constructing, and operating large-scale data centers. This experience has been applied to the AWS platform and infrastructure. AWS data centers are housed in nondescript facilities, and critical facilities have extensive setback and military grade perimeter control berms as well as other natural boundary protection. Physical access is strictly controlled both at the perimeter and at building ingress points by professional security staff utilizing video surveillance, state-of-the-art intrusion detection systems, and other electronic means. Authorized staff must pass two-factor authentication no fewer than three times to access data center floors. All visitors and contractors are required to present identification and are signed in and continually escorted by authorized staff. Amazon only provides data center access and information to employees who have a legitimate business need for such privileges. When an employee no longer has a business need for these privileges, his or her access is immediately revoked, even if they continue to be an employee of Amazon or Amazon Web Services. All physical and electronic access to data centers by Amazon employees is logged and audited routinely. Inc42 employees do not have control or access to AWS centers, servers, network equipment, or storage.

 **Logical Access Controls:** Inc42 is the assigned administrator of its infrastructure, and only designated authorized Inc42 operations team members have access to configure the infrastructure on an as-needed basis behind a two-factor authenticated virtual private network. Specific private keys are required for individual servers, and keys are stored in a secure and encrypted location.

 **Intrusion Detection and Prevention:** Unusual network patterns or suspicious behavior are among Inc42’s biggest concerns for infrastructure hosting and management. AWS intrusion detection and prevention systems (IDS/IPS) rely on both signature-based and algorithm-based security to help identify traffic patterns that are similar to known attack methods. IDS/IPS involves tightly controlling the size and make-up of the attack surface, employing intelligent detection controls at data entry points, and developing and deploying technologies that automatically remedy dangerous situations, as well as preventing known threats from accessing the system in the first place. We do not provide direct access to security event forensics, but we do provide access to our engineering and customer support teams during and after any unscheduled downtime.

 **Disclosure of Information to Third Parties**

Inc42 may disclose your personal data with your consent, or as necessary to provide the Services to you.

By visiting, accessing, attending or using Inc42’s products, services or events, you consent to the disclosure of your Information to certain categories of third parties in the manner described below. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the policies or practices of any of these third parties.

 **Service Providers**

Inc42 relies on third party vendors and service providers to provide support and assistance for its products, services, and events (“Service Providers”), and we may disclose your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to these Service Providers to the extent necessary to support our products, services or events, or as otherwise set forth below.

 **Event Registration**

Inc42 uses third parties, such as Meraevents and Explara, to process registration for Inc42 events and programs. Inc42 may provide your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to such registration services when you register for an Inc42 event or program. In addition, as discussed below, Inc42 (or its third party registration service) may provide your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to companies that sponsor or underwrite portions of an event that you register for, attend, or view.

 **Web Hosts**

Inc42’s website services are hosted by WpEngine, an enterprise web hosting platform. All Information obtained and stored by Inc42’s websites processed and stored on servers that are owned and operated by WordPress.

 **Third Party Websites**

Inc42 offers the ability to share Inc42 content on Third Party Websites, including social networking and blogging services such as LinkedIn or Facebook, through “plugins” or “widgets” (such as LinkedIn’s “in” button or Facebook’s “Like” button). When you elect to share content and information with others on Third Party Websites, Inc42 may transmit your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to such Third Party Websites. This Information may be visible on the Third Party Website to anyone who has access to that content or Information. Your decision to share information in this manner is completely voluntary. You should ensure that you are comfortable with how Third Party Websites may share your Information by reviewing their privacy policies and/or modifying your privacy settings directly on those Third Party Websites.

 **URL/Referrer Header Information**

When you visit Inc42 websites, certain information about the content or activities you have engaged in on Inc42 may be reflected in the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) for the page you are viewing on Inc42 (i.e., the Internet “address,” commonly displayed in the browser window). For example, the date or title of an article you are viewing may appear in the URL for that page. In addition, if you are logged into a Inc42 account, certain account information (may be visible in the URL when you visit your account on Inc42. If you leave Inc42 to visit a third party website, including when you click on an advertisement or link or when you share information through a social plug-in (like the Linked In “in” button), the information contained in the URL may be transmitted to the third party website by your browser.

 **Advertisers and Analytics Services**

Inc42 uses third party advertisers, including ad networks, to provide advertising on its websites. In addition, as discussed in (“Analytics Services”), Inc42 uses third party analytics products to obtain information about how users are using and interacting with Inc42. These third parties may receive Information (including Personally Identifying Information) from Inc42 as discussed in greater detail in (“Security and Protection of Personally Identifying Information”).

 **Law Enforcement/Legal Process**

We may disclose your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to comply with any law, regulation or legal request; enforce, apply, or investigate breaches of our terms of use and other agreements; respond to public requests; or protect the rights, property, user experience or safety of Inc42, our employees, our users, or others. This can include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

 **Comments and Public Posts; Sharing on Third-Party Websites**

Inc42 encourages active participation by users, including through comments on Inc42. However, please be aware that if you voluntarily disclose Information, personal or otherwise, on Inc42, that Information can be viewed, collected and used by others, including other users, search engines, advertisers, third party applications developers, and anyone with access to Inc42. Inc42 has no control over the use, collection or disclosure of any Information that you post publicly on Inc42.

 **Change of Control**

If Inc42, or substantially all of its assets, is acquired by another company or party, user Information will be one of the assets transferred or acquired by the purchaser. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that any purchaser of Inc42 or its assets may continue to collect, use and disclose your Information as set forth in this Policy.

 **Third-Party Advertising on Inc42**

Inc42 may allow third-party advertising serving companies, including ad networks (“Advertisers”), to display advertisements or provide other advertising services on Inc42. These third party Advertisers may use techniques other than HTTP cookies to recognize your computer or device and/or to collect and record demographic and other Information about you, including your activities on or off Inc42. These techniques may be used directly on Inc42. Please keep in mind that your web browser may not permit you to block the use of these techniques, and that browser settings that block conventional cookies may have no effect on such techniques.

Advertisers may use the information collected to display advertisements that are tailored to your interests or background and/or associate such information with your subsequent visits, purchases or other activities on other websites. Advertisers may also share this information with their clients or other third parties.

 **Inc42 has no responsibility for the technologies, tools or practices of the Advertisers that provide advertising and related services on Inc42**. This Privacy Policy does not cover any collection, use or disclosure of Information by Advertisers who provide advertising and related services on Inc42. These Advertisers’ information gathering practices, including their policies regarding the use of cookies and other tracking technologies, are governed entirely by their own privacy policies, not this one.

Inc42 currently may be using one or more of the following Advertisers to provide advertising and related services on Inc42. If you would like to know about their information gathering and privacy practices, please visit the links below

 **Analytics Services**

In addition, Inc42 uses third party analytics providers and products to obtain, compile and analyze Information (that may include Personally Identifying Information) about how users are using and interacting with Inc42. Inc42 may provide Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to these analytics providers for the purpose of obtaining statistics and other information about how users are using and interacting with Inc42. These analytics providers may use tracking techniques other than HTTP cookies to recognize your computer or device and/or to collect or compile this information. These techniques may be used directly on Inc42. Inc42 has no responsibility for the technologies, tools or practices of the third parties that providing analytics products and services to Inc42. Please also keep in mind that your web browser may not permit you to block the use of these techniques, and that browser settings that block conventional cookies may have no effect on such techniques.

 **Security and Protection of Personally Identifying Information**

We have implemented reasonable security measures and practices in an effort to protect the confidentiality of your Personally Identifying Information (other than Personally Identifying Information that you have elected to disclose to others). However, no security system is impenetrable. It may be possible for third parties to intercept or access the information you provide to Inc42. Inc42 cannot guarantee the security of your Personally Identifying Information, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to Inc42. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password(s) and computer or device, and to log off when using any shared computer.

 **Email or Text Message Communications**

We may contact you by e-mail, text message or other equivalent electronic communications if you access Inc42 products or services or register for events or other content or services provided by Inc42. By visiting or using Inc42 content, products or services, or registering for or attending Inc42 events, you specifically consent to the receipt of these e-mail or text message communications. If you do not want to receive emails, text messages or other communications from us, please notify us by email at support@inc42.com and include sufficient information for us to identify your account, including your Name, Email Address (or Cellphone Number) and the specifics of your request. If you unsubscribe, Inc42 may still contact you via email or text message for administrative purposes or concerning any products, services or events for which you have registered or are using.

 **Changes to the Privacy Policy**

Inc42 retains the discretion to amend or modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use and disclosure of Information we obtain is subject to the later of: (1) the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such Information is collected or (2) any subsequent Privacy Policy of which you have notice. If we make material changes to the way we collect, use or disclose Personally Identifying Information, we will notify you by posting a clear and prominent announcement on Inc42 or through a direct communication. Your continued access to or use of Inc42 following notice of material changes to this Privacy Policy shall constitute consent to any amendments and/or modifications. Your use of Inc42 is entirely voluntary, and you may discontinue use of Inc42 at any time.

 **How to Contact Us**

Inc42 welcomes any questions or comments you may have regarding this Privacy Policy or its implementation. Any such questions or comments should be submitted via email to support@inc42.com or directed to the address below. We will undertake reasonable efforts to resolve or address your concern.
